<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[I code better drunk]]></title>
  <link href="http://hwang0214.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://hwang0214.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-22T01:07:39-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://hwang0214.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Harrison Wang]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Non-techie in a techie world]]></title>
    <link href="http://hwang0214.github.com/blog/2013/02/20/non-technical-founder-of-a-tech-start-up/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-20T23:13:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://hwang0214.github.com/blog/2013/02/20/non-technical-founder-of-a-tech-start-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the story of a non-techie partnered with an MIT programmer to co-found a tech start-up. After successfully manuevering in the ecommerce space for two years, I became increasingly drawn to the tech start-up scene in NYC. Fortunately, I was not one of the masses who had to scour networking events to find my technical co-founder.</p>

<p>Through mutual friends, I was able to draw significant interest from a couple of brilliant programmers from MIT and Caltech and finally decided on a team to join me. We were also able to gardner interest from several executives and formed a board of advisors with a member of the Fortune 500 executive clique and an award-winning documentary producer. But this blog isn&#8217;t about the company, it is about how I, as a non-technical co-founder of a technology start-up decided to go to programming school at Flatiron School for 12-weeks, to learn how to better understand and interact with my technical co-founder and our talented (yes, shameless plug) group of programmers.</p>

<p><strong>Being the technical idiot</strong><br />
When we first started a few months back, I was in on all the meetings, including the ones where our development team would brainstorm how to build things. I always found the logic and and conversations interesting - although I would be lost in &lt; 5 minutes. I will never forget the time I &#8220;tried&#8221; to be helpful: two members of the programming team were telling me how we needed to get Github accounts to share code, and I brilliantly suggested that they use Google Docs to share code (since you can see changes being made in real-time). They laughed, and that was the last time I ever gave a suggestion related to programming. I ended up not being involved in most of the technical brainstorming sessions.</p>

<p><strong>Why Still Flatiron?</strong>
A lot of people questioned why I stuck with Flatiron School, even after the company started drawing interest from VCs in the Valley, recruited several other talented programmers for the summer (confirming I would never code for the company), had to work on provisional patents, and preparing for our official launch in the summer with several enterprises, including Fortune 500 companies. In fact, a couple of friends actually advised that I shouldn&#8217;t learn how to code because it would change the way I view how to solve problems. Of all people, it was my co-founder who said to go through with it as it would make me a better communicator and manager for the company.</p>

<p><strong>Learning Every Day</strong><br />
I have learned a tremendous amount in the 2 and a half weeks I&#8217;ve been a Flatiron School. Learning Github was an amazing, albeit frustrating experience, as it helped me realize the value and purpose of needing Github repositories (as opposed to Google Docs). <br /></p>

<p>To be honest, I don&#8217;t know if taking Flatiron has made me more excited about learning how to code or more afraid of attempting. I&#8217;ve always wanted to be able to build small, custom apps that I could use for myself; however as I talk every night with our programming team, I realize just how wide the gap between my logic is from theirs.</p>

<p><strong>Inside the Mind</strong>
I am learning how to communicate better in technical settings, as well as better understanding the mindset and actions of a programmer. Before, I would never understand how my co-founder could stay up literally all night, trying to figure out a problem. But after being engrossed in the hacker&#8217;s scene and seeing how people can&#8217;t sleep until they figure out a problem, makes me understand what&#8217;s so engrossing and addictive about finishing a problem.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I am Learning to Code]]></title>
    <link href="http://hwang0214.github.com/blog/2013/02/12/why-i-am-learning-to-code/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-12T08:05:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://hwang0214.github.com/blog/2013/02/12/why-i-am-learning-to-code</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol>
<li><p><em>Self-Improvement</em><br />
Continual learning keeps the mind humble. Not knowing what you don&#8217;t know can lead to  dangerous situations, espeically for entreprenuers. Continual learning pushes me to set higher standards and more well-thought out goals.</p></li>
<li><p><em>Build My Own Apps</em><br />
I have always enjoyed brainstorming and discussing ways to make things more efficient. There are several ideas that I would like to test out and build, if for nothing else,  to make my life more efficient.</p></li>
<li><p><em>Become Part of the Community</em> <br />
The worldwide tech scenes have exploded in recent years. People from all backgrounds are leaving their jobs to flock to coding schools and communities. There is arguably no community that lends itself to a more diverse set of skills and interests, which creates awesome learning opportunities and unqiue relationships.</p></li>
<li><p><em>Learn the Lingo</em> <br />
One of the biggest peeves VCs and Angels have is when an entreprenuer says &#8220;I&#8217;m the non-technical co-founder, I don&#8217;t know or understand the technical features of my product.&#8221;
Having a grasp of the basics of coding allows me to drive the technical conversations even if my technical co-founder isn&#8217;t present.</p></li>
<li><p><em>Part of Our Lives</em> <br />
Technology is ingrained in our lives, and will only increase in importance as more and more things become automated. Its always great to be at the forefront of future.</p></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
